Okay, hold on a second. You're at Rick
Ross's house. Uh, how old were you when
Hustling came out? Like what? Like two.
>> What year that came out?
>> 2006.
>> Oh, yes sir. I was two. I was 2 years
old.
>> Jeez.
Hey Colts fans, I'm JJ Stankovitz and
welcome in to another episode of the
Colts Show in Indianapolis Colts
podcast. We are presented by our friends
at Microsoft Surface Co-Pilot Plus PC.
On today's episode, you're going to get
to hear from Georgia linebacker CJ Allen
and LSU safety AJ Holly, or maybe I
should say Colts linebacker CJ Allen and
Colts safety AJ Holly. I had a chance to
catch up with both of them a couple of
minutes after both of them got drafted
by the Colts last week. Really cool
chats with both of them. Uh AJ Holly was
at Rick Ross' house. I was not at Rick
Ross's house. I was here over Zoom at
the Indiana Farm Bureau Football Center.
One thing you'll see on the video
version, you won't see me. You'll just
see CJ Allen and AJ Holly had a bit of
an issue with our Zoom, but still more
important to see them than it is me. Uh,
really cool chats with both those guys.
Let's get to them right now. Starting
with Georgia linebacker CJ Allen right
after this. The Colt Show is presented
by Microsoft Surface Co-Pilot Plus PC,
where every day is game day. Greatness
in the NFL starts long before kickoff.
It's built in the quiet hours of
preparation and the discipline to turn
insights into action. The Indianapolis
Colts rely on Microsoft Surface Co-Pilot
Plus PCs to turn preparation into
performance. With real-time AI powered
insights right on the sideline, coaches
and players can make smarter, faster
decisions when it matters most. From the
field to the front office, Microsoft
Surface Co-Pilot Plus PCs are
transforming how the Indianapolis Colts
prepare, strategize, and win. This isn't
just about football. It's about
unlocking potential wherever the game is
played. It's my pleasure to be joined
here on the podcast by linebacker CJ
Allen. CJ, congrats, man. Uh, what was
the moment like for you getting that
call from Chris Ballard and the Colts on
Friday night?
It was definitely it was an exciting
feeling honestly you know sitting there
waiting for the call know waiting for a
team just to believe in me and coach
they also believe in me I mean I feel
like they kind of been believing me from
the start honestly I thought we had a
good I go back to the form meeting I
think we had a good form meeting it goes
to the zoom that came my pro day
honestly man it just been like I say
it's been there since the start honestly
>> who are you watching the draft with and
and who are you celebrating with tonight
>> I'm celebrating my family my my close
family members my sibling my So we we we
were kind of deep in that thing. I got a
big family.
>> I I saw you're what? The youngest of
six. Is that right?
>> I'm the youngest of six. Yep. Three boys
and three girls. Yeah. I'm the youngest.
>> How how competitive was the uh the Allen
household. And how did that kind of help
you out? You know, growing up in in that
as the youngest kid,
>> man. Super super competitive household,
man. It forced me to be tough. Uh I'll
say a lot of uh you know, like I I hated
losing. So a lot of games younger early
on when I was younger they would beat me
in. So man, they just taught me just,
you know, little things like I look back
on like to keep going. But it was super
competitive. I just I want to be better
than them in every aspect. What it is
and my brother scored six point, I want
to score seven points. Like I had to be
better than them.
>> Your uh one of your brothers played at
uh Southeast Missouri State linebacker.
Is that right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> What did you learn from him? Just like
I'm, you know, assuming watching him go
through high school just like seeing
what he did as a linebacker. And do you
take some parts of his game and and
incorporate them into yours? Uh, no
doubt. I think he's just physical. I
take take that aspect into it.
Obviously, he's fast also, but man, I
just take u from him just uh
perseverance, man. He's just super
tough, man. I think I just seen him
battle battle through a lot of things. A
lot of battle through adversity and come
out with top. So, man, I'm super super
proud of him. Give a lot of credit to
him. A lot of credit to my middle
brother, too. My middle brother, you
know, he played ball as well, but he he
didn't go to college. He just went to
school. But, um, he just taught me, man,
to believe in myself. He always told me
I was the one. So, uh, he instead
accomplished me too just always up with
me for sure.
>> There aren't many freshman who walk into
Georgia and and that big of a program
that's had that kind of, you know,
success at your position going, you
know, Rocoan Smith, Quay Walker, Nico
Dean, those guys, and not many freshman
walk in and start like you did. You
talked about perseverance. Um, what did
what did that kind of trait of yours
like that ability to persevere through
things, how did that allow you to get on
the field so quickly at Georgia? Man, I
just like you said, I just been able
because just like I mean SEC ball as a
freshman, you going to make mistakes. So
I think next play mentality, you know,
they started back in practice back in
fall camp long days. So I look back on
those thing that's how I learned that
especially as a freshman knowing that
you know you got a lot of older guys
around you. They can't know when you
make the call get the call out and do
your job and also like make sure you
know everyone else was doing their job
also too. So it just kind of just let me
just know like hey I ain't going to be
perfect but it's not a mistake as long
as you don't make the same mistake
again. And it just just learn a lesson
from at that point.
>> How did you handle that? Like being like
the next in line among like Georgia
linebackers like you know taking maybe
their legacy but making it your own as
well.
>> Mhm. Yeah man. Like I said man I don't
see it as a challenge man. It's a lot
man. I just look at it as like this this
a great opportunity. And also man
whenever whenever I fight the game this
this is a lot. I always remind myself
this what it's supposed to feel like.
This what I was aiming toward. I'm not
doing nothing small. I'm not doing
nothing for that that anyone can do. I'm
doing stuff that that many can't do that
many talk about doing. So me just, you
know, when when it gets to that time, I
realize, hey, this what I want. This
what I always dreamed of. You know, my
my whole the whole goal was to eat, so I
can't complain when there's a lot of
food on the table.
>> That's incredible. I love that line. Um,
who who was like a guy who made you
better practicing against him at
Georgia?
>> Uh, against him, man, I was like, man,
take Rage. Uh, uh, uh, Jared Jared
Wilson. You got uh even sometimes uh uh
uh Mims or Mary's Mims man. Uh obviously
said Ben pray man going against him you
know center head in in that a gap man.
Drew Bobo man goes on and on. Even this
past year you got the speed receiver
like Zack Branch you know running back
you know my guy Rod Robertson we came in
together. Uh Nate Freak man name goes
on. Whenever you come to Georgia you
know man you f to play against practice
against talent every single day.
>> What what did you learn? You know you
talked about like Wilson and Rattled.
Those are two pretty good interior guys.
Like what did you learn about how to
like maybe like shed blocks like take on
a guy who's probably got 70 pounds on
you, you know, on those play.
>> Yep. Definitely. Uh they always say
bigger. So, you know, you got to go get
them before they get you. In the
linebacker room in Georgia, we always
say, man, force equal mass time
acceleration. So, if I speed up and hit
them with enough force and my mass, man,
I
I'll be good.
>> Right on. I want to get you out of here
on this, CJ. Um, give me your your three
favorite plays from college. Like the
ones where you look back on your time at
Georgia and you're like, you know, that
those are the ones that you think about
that stick with you and are ones that
maybe, you know, Colts fans should go
try to, you know, find on YouTube and go
watch here.
>> I think 2024 uh versus Florida, my
interception, that was pretty cool. Um,
what else? What else? Uh, I just Oh, my
2024 game, Georgia Tech, you know,
tackling the H King on goal. I thought
it was pretty cool. It was like an eight
overtime type of situation. And man,
just uh this previous this previous
year, I said the punch out versus
Kentucky. I think it was just pretty
cool. Me sharing the block, getting to
the ball, punching the ball out.
>> Right on, CJ Allen. Man,
congratulations. Welcome to Indie. We're
looking forward to you getting up here
and uh getting to work here with the
Colts. Congrats, man.
>> Thank you. It's my pleasure to be joined
here on the Colts show by safety AJ
Hollyy who was selected on Friday in the
third round of the NFL draft. AJ man,
congratulations. Uh what does it feel
like or what did it feel like to get
that call from an Indianapolis number on
Friday,
>> man? It it felt amazing, you know. Um,
that was a call that that that that was
overdue, you know, and um, you know, and
I'm just ready to make whoever pay,
whoever pass up on me, I'm ready to make
all all 31 teams pay because I'm with
I'm with the team that that that that
drafted me. So, just getting that phone
call, you know, it felt amazing. It just
what I've been through it, I know it
just showed a lot of kids with where I'm
from, like it's possible. So, that phone
call definitely felt amazing.
>> Who are you uh celebrating tonight?
>> I'm in Houston, Texas. I'm from I'm
originally from Houston, Texas. I'm at
uh they just said Rick on his house. So,
you know, um it's a big celebration
going on and I'm glad I'm I'm a coach.
>> Okay, hold hold on a second. You're at
Rick Ross's house. Uh how old were you
when Hustling came out? Like what, like
two?
>> What year that came out?
>> 2006.
>> Oh, yes, sir. I was two. I was 2 years
old.
>> Gee, that's I'm I'm feeling I'm feeling
super old here right now. But that's
awesome. Uh what's your connection to to
Rick Ross?
Um, he's my cousin on my on my dad's
side.
>> How about that? Um, okay. To Let's tell
tell me about the the shirt you got
there. It says Long Live Trey on it for
our audio listeners. Uh, what does that
mean to you? And uh what what you know,
what does it mean to you to honor
someone who clearly meant a lot to you
on this such an important day for you,
>> man? It means a lot, you know. Um and
just him being from where I'm from and
you know him him just showing me like
okay what not to do you know just us
growing up together we was very close
and um that was a very very close
friends of mine like right now I call
his mama my auntie and and I call his
brother my cousin like that's how close
he was like every day growing up you
know I run over there we'll play
football in the yard and things like
that but his passion for football just
faded away a little early and he and he
wandered off to other things and you
know end up tragically and end up and
and him passing. So, you know, I kind of
took that and I kind of stored it in my
brain. Okay, AJ, you're not going to go
down that path. You going to stick to
this. And the game just stuck to me, you
know, um the game the game of football
stuck to me. And um you know, um he was
an example. And he not just an example,
you know, that he was everything that I
wanted to be just in a different body
just by him showing me, okay, AJ, don't
go down this path, go down another path.
And I just can't thank him enough to for
that. And I just love him. I I love him.
my guardian angel.
>> What does football mean to you, Ben? AJ,
>> football means a lot, you know. Um, just
being where I'm from, football changed
and saved my life in so many ways. Like
it was days where where me and he were
going to practice together and it was
days where when I'm getting out of
practice, I'm coming home playing with
him and um just by by by football just
calling me to practice that uh uh some
some hours before he passed, you know.
Um that that means a lot. Like that
saved my life. Like I could have, you
know, if every day I'm playing with you
and I'm doing things with you and and
football calling me and you pass, I get
that call right after the football
practice. You know, football saved my
life. You know, just being a child where
I'm from and being a kid where I'm from
is is you got plenty of op,
but a lot of kids don't have the
football option. You don't have the
right option. You don't have a good
option. And football was just the best
option for me. And I fell in love with
it since I was four years old. I've been
playing since I was four years old. And
and football is my life, man. like
without football, I don't know where I'd
be right now.
>> Do you like do you ever think about like
how inspiring you can be to, you know,
kids around where you're at, you know,
from the Houston area of just like, hey
man, like you can make it. You can, you
know, use football as this vehicle and,
you know, look where you wound up.
You're 78th overall pick to the Colts.
That's that's an incredible
accomplishment.
>> I think about that every day. Like right
now I got two little nieces and I I just
want to show them like I just want to
show them like like your uncle just he
trying to pave a way. Like he trying to
show y'all what to do. He trying to give
y'all the blueprint and so y'all could
build something. So with this blueprint
I just hope every child and every kid
where I'm from build something. You know
I'm just laying out the blueprint for
for the ones behind me and I just want
to give the most gain back that I can
and and that's possible. So, I'm uh I'm
going to be giving back a lot and I'm
going to be just, you know, a good
mentor to to to to the younger youth
because I know like I was screaming out
for help, you know, as a kid and and
like I wasn't realizing it and and so
was nobody else, but the one thing that
was was football and just football just
grabbed me by the arm and said, "I got
you." And just drug me along. So,
>> when did you realize when did you
realize that like this could be a
reality for you? like, you know, getting
that call from the Colts and, you know,
making it now into the league and, you
know, starring at LSU and Houston and
and these places like when when did that
kind of hit you that this could happen?
>> Can you repeat that?
>> Yeah. When did it when did it kind of
hit you that like this could be a
reality for you? Um, you know, that like
football could take you to this place.
>> Um, um, when I realized, you know, just
once I enter college, you know, and once
I, um, made my to the university history
to be real. And I had in my head that,
you know, um it was no doubt that I was
going to make to NFL. Like I seen past
college, I seen past high school ball.
And the only thing that was on my mind
is NFL. Like it was every Sunday
morning, every Sunday night. Like me and
my mother, we going we I'm sitting on
her bed and we watching NFL, we watching
the Texans, we watching whoever. Like
and the Texans played the coast a lot.
So I watched a lot of those games. you
know, um, just football was just always
something that I knew I was going to do
and I knew I was going to be good at.
And also my mother, like she even played
power to put football. So I just say,
you know, football was always there for
me and always surrounded me in every
which way.
>> What position did your mom play?
>> She played linebacker, quarterback,
running back, safety in the end.
>> Heck yeah. So is she like giving you you
guys watching like film together? She's
giving you tips and stuff.
>> She She thinks she know more ball than
me.
I swear she does. She think she know
more behind.
>> That's awesome. Uh, I want to get you
out of here on this, AJ. Um, you know,
for some some folks here in Indie who
are, you know, getting to know you,
getting to know you as a a player, as a
person. Um, give me like your three
favorite plays you ever made in college,
whether it's at New Mexico, Houston, or
LSU.
>> New Mexico when I take my uh my first
game, my first game playing after I
caught the interception, I chase someone
down to the one yard line. I punched the
ball out for a touchback, you know. Um
that was right out of halftime and you
know it was a momentum swing. They would
have scored but I stopped them so it was
a momentum swing for us.
I say my first interception at LSU my my
my Florida interception when I
intercepted DJ Lway from the post I
intercepted a dig that I seen on film
and another one is my TCU TCU game. I
had two interceptions and one was I was
the low hole player in cover well I was
the deep middle run through in cover two
and the quarterback tried to look me off
and I went that way but I knew he was
coming back so I was able to transition
quickly and I intercepted the ball so
those three plays was was was one was
three of the best plays I ever made.
>> Right on. Looking forward to more than
three of those plays uh here with the
Colts, man. Can't wait to get you up
here and get you get you on board with
the team, man. Looking forward to
watching you this season. For
>> sure. Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you, AJ.